Preliminary Inventory to the Harold Keith Thompson Collection, 1932-1993
Hoover Institution Archives
Harold Keith Thompson Collection,
1932-1993
55006
Thompson, Harold Keith, 1922-
23 manuscript boxes 9.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Leaflets, newsletters, pamphlets, newspaper and periodical issues, clippings, correspondence, and writings, relating to fascist and other rightist political groups in the United States and Europe after World War II. Includes a few leftist publications.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1955.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Afro-Americans--Segregation.; Anti-communist movements.; Antisemitism; Fascism.; Nationalism.; Europe.; United States--Politics and government.
Container List
- Personal papers and manuscripts (Box 1.)
- U.S. nationalist and rightist tendencies (Box 2.-5.)
- German nationalism (Box 6.)
- Italian nationalism (Box 7.)
- General leftist trends
- Rearmament of Eastern and Western Europe (Box 8.)
- Segregation literature (Box 9.)
- Anti-Semitic literature (Box 10.)
- Miscellaneous material (Box 11.)
- Swedish nationalism
- The Arab question (Box 12.)
- Germans and politics in Canada
- South African materials (Box 13.)
- Addenda on American nationalism and Jews, 1973
- Gilbreath, Frederick (correspondence between General Gilbreath and H. Keith Thompson concerning their judgment of the War Crimes Trial, Nuremberg, with particular reference to Grand Admiral Karl Doenitz, plus a résumé of General Gilbreath's career), 1 envelope
- Gross, Kurt, defendant (defense documents of the "Flyers case 12-43" tried at Dachau in 1947 October. Accused were: Dr. Kurt Gross, Eduard Mack, Adolf Mattes, and Rudolf Spletzer. Contains petitions, affidavits, applications, and miscellaneous correspondence pertaining to this case), 1 envelope
- Serial issues and leaflets issued by American fascist and white supremacist organizations, 1964-1979. Includes some communist and miscellaneous issuances
- Serials and newspapers (Box 14.)
  - American Hebrew
  - Appeal to Reason
  - Die Brücke
  - Common Sense
  - Die deutsche Gemeinschaft
  - Die Eiche
  - Expose
  - Grassroots
  - Headlines and What's behind Them
  - Haimkehrer
  - Die Nation
  - Natinform (S. P. Int.)
  - National Guardian
  - National Renaissance Bulletin
  - Stille Hilfe für Kriegsgefangene und Internierte
  - Volksruf
  - Union
  - Welt ohne Krieg
  - Widerhall
  - Williams Intelligence Summary
  - Women's Voice
  - Today
  - Eüropäische Nationale
  - Der Trommler
  - Das Weltgewissen
  - La Legione
- Newspaper issues and leaflets issued by American fascist and other right-wing organizations, 1979-1980; and the typewritten memoirs of Charles Bewley, Irish nationalist and diplomat
- Additional serials and newspapers (Box 15.)
  - Deutsche Freiheit
  - Der Freiwillige; für einigkeit und Fecht und Freiheit
  - N.Y. Bulletin (published by Friends of Portugal)
  - National Socialist Bulletin
  - National Socialist World
  - Rockwell Report
  - Storm Trooper
  - Western Destiny
- Correspondence, writings clippings, pamphlets, and serial issues, 1949-1981, relating to fascist and other right-wing political organizations in Germany and the U.S. (Box 15.-16.)
- Correspondence, writings, serial issues, newsletters, leaflets and other printed matter, 1960-1983, relating to fascist and other right-wing organizations in the U.S. and elsewhere; and photocopies of miscellaneous letters, 1935-1945, signed by various Nazi leaders (Box 16.)
- Correspondence, writings, legal briefs, questionnaires, newsletters, newspaper and magazine issues, clippings and other printed material, photographs, and miscellany, 1932-1993, relating to fascist and other rightist political groups and causes in the U.S. and Europe, especially Germany, before and after World War II. Includes a photocopy of a letter by Jefferson Davis, 1883. In English, German, and French (Box 18.-23.)